Finding Aid for Office of Student Conflict Resolution (University of Michigan) records, 1962-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Statement of Student Rights and Responsibilities 1989-1992 (SSRR)
  - Student Survey
    - Report 1992 (Box 1)
    - Responses 1992 (Box 1)
  - Town Hall Meeting Minutes 1992 (Box 1)
  - Working Paper on Codes of Campus Conduct 1990 (Box 1)
- Code of Student Conduct 1994-1998
  The Code of Student Conduct series, 1994-1998, (1.0 linear foot), is an alphabetically arranged series containing materials related to the development, review and implementation of the Code of Student Conduct. The process and work of the Code Workgroup is detailed by minutes and agenda. The development of the code is particularly well documented, and the series contains a good number of code drafts with comment by committee members, campus administrators, and outside consultants, reflecting the ongoing development of the code and the thought-process behind it. Faculty and student input into the code is also well represented in the record group; feedback and opinions are contained in the drop box response and focus group files. In 1998, the code was subject to both an internal and external review process; final reports in this series succinctly reflect their work and provide an evaluative tool for the effectiveness of the code after its implementation.
  - Development
    - Background References 1995 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box 2)
    - Drafts with Comments
      - Undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - April 1995 (Box 2)
      - August 1995 (Box 2)
      - September 1995 (Box 2)
      - October 20, 1995 (Box 2)
      - October 23, 1995 (Box 2)
      - November 1, 1995 (Box 2)
      - November 3, 1995 (Box 2)
      - November 6, 1995 (Box 2)
      - November 8, 1995 (Box 2)
      - November 10, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Drop Box Responses 1995 (Box 2)
    - Focus Groups
      - Individual Feedback Forms 1995 (Box 2)
      - Scenarios Worksheet 1995 (Box 2)
      - Session Summaries 1995 (Box 2)
      - Workgroup Background Materials 1995 (Box 2)
    - General Counsel Comment on Code 1995
      [CR RESTRICTED until January 1 2095; removed to vault]
    - Outside Comment 1995 (Box 2)
    - Regent Discussion
      - April 21, 1995 (cassette) (Box 2)
      - November 16, 1995 (cassette) (Box 2)
    - Workgroup
      - Minutes and Agenda 1995 (Box 2)
      - Misc. Notes and Drawings 1995 (Box 2)
  - Protest 1995 (Box 2)
  - Review
    - External Review Team Report 1998 (Box 2)
    - Internal Review
      - Code Implementation Review Committee
        - Correspondence 1998, 2 folders (Box 2)
        - Membership Roster 1998 (Box 2)
        - Minutes and Agenda 1998 (Box 2)
        - "Myth of 'No Code', A Special Report," 1998 (Box 2)
        - Report October 21, 1998 (Box 2)
        - Timeline 1998 (Box 2)
      - Focus Groups
        - Faculty/Staff 1998 (Box 2)
        - Student 1998 (Box 2)
      - Internal Assessment of the Office of Conflict Resolution 1998 (Box 2)
      - Survey
        - Faculty/Staff 1998 (Box 2)
        - Students 1998 (Box 2)
- Guidelines, Worksheets, and Forms 1998-2005, undated
  The Guidelines, Worksheets, and Forms series, 1998-2005, (0.5 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically. The series contains guidelines set forth by the Council for the Advancement of Standards in Higher Education (CAS), resources used in the Office of Student Conflict Resolution processes as well as, guidelines and worksheets for initial meetings with complainants, victims, and witnesses
  - Council for the Advancement of Standards in Higher Education (CAS) and The Code of Student Conduct 1998, undated (Box 3)
  - Initial Meeting Part 1 2005 (Box 3)
  - Initial Meeting Part 2 2005 (Box 3)
  - Sanctioning Resources 1998-2001 (Box 3)
  - Sexual Harassment Complaints Guide 1998 (Box 3)
- Training Manuals 1993-2005
  The Training Manuals series, 1993-2005, (1.0 linear feet) is divided into the files General (.25 linear feet), Judicial Board (0.25 linear feet), and Resolution Board (0.5 linear feet). The series is arranged chronologically. It contains materials produced for training manuals for use in a variety of workshops, training sessions, and OSCR adjudicating boards-all manuals were originally housed in three-ring binders.
  - General (2000-2004)
    - Aggression Management Workshop 2000 (Box 3)
    - Housing Student Conflict Resolution Training 2002 (Box 3)
    - Student Advisor Corps March 25, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Student Organization and Recognition (SOAR) Fall 2004 (Box 3)
  - Judicial Board 1993-1996
    - 1993 (Box 3)
    - 1993 Pre Code Evaluations (Box 3)
    - 1994 Training Tapes (Box 3)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 3)
    - 1994-1995 Speeches (Box 3)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Resolution Board 1996-2005
    - Winter 1996 (Box 3)
    - Fall 1996 (Box 3)
    - 1997 (Box 4)
    - 1999 (Box 4)
    - 2000 (Box 4)
    - 2001, 2 folders (Box 4)
      (includes Power Point Presentations)
    - 2002, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - 2003 (Box 4)
    - 2004, 2 folders (Box 4)
      (includes Participant's Evaluations)
    - 2005 (Box 4)
- Public Relations 1992-2006
  Public Relations series, 1992-2006, (1.0 linear foot) is arranged alphabetically and is mostly comprised of a series of scrapbooked newspaper clippings from The Michigan Daily and other local newspapers covering the years from 1992 to 2006. Most of the articles deal with the reception of the Code of Student Conduct. All articles relate to the Office of Student Conflict Resolution in some manner. A few folders also touch on media relations, publicity efforts, and website development.
  - Bookmark Marketing 2002 (Box 4)
  - Media Forms and Publication Guidelines 2001, Undated (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 6 folders
    - 1992-1994 (Box 4)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 4)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 4)
    - 1995-1999 (Box 5)
    - 1999-2002 (Box 5)
    - 2002-2006 (Box 5)
  - Open House Publicity Efforts 2002 (Box 5)
  - Website Development 2002 (Box 5)
- Reviews and Reports 1998-2005
  The Reviews and Reports series, 1998-2005, (0.5 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically and includes general reviews of the Office of Student Conflict Resolution, reviews of the Code of Student Conduct and training session evaluations.
  - Code of Student Conduct Annual Report 1998 (Box 5)
  - Greek Activities Review Panel Manual (Box 5)
  - Office of Student Conflict Resolution Annual Report 2003-2004 (Box 5)
  - Office of Student Conflict Resolution Informal Report 2001-2002 (Box 5)
  - Office of Student Conflict Resolution (OSCR) Review 1998 (Box 5)
  - Student Organization and Recognition (SOAR) Advisory Committee Report April 2005 (Box 5)
  - Training Evaluations 2002-2003 (Box 5)
- Publications 2000, Undated
  The Publication series, 2000 and undated, contains one folder of pamphlets, booklets, and guides published by the Office of Student Conflict Resolution.
  - Brochures, flyers, pamphlets created by OSCR (Box 5)
- Surveys 1992
  The Surveys series, 1992, (2.0 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically and includes the completed surveys of 171 faculty and 3050 students. Issued in the summer of 1992, OSCR distributed the survey to ascertain faculty and student opinions on the proposed Code of Student Conduct. The student surveys are housed in their original three-ring binders. Some of the data mined from the surveys is present in Box 1 of the earlier accessioned record group. A few surveys were removed and arranged based on subject; they are present in a folder in this series.
  - Faculty Survey Responses no. 0001-0171 (Box 6)
  - Removed and Analyzed Surveys (Box 6)
  - Student Surveys
    - no. 0001-0500 (Box 6)
    - no. 0501-1000 (Box 6)
    - no. 1001-1500 (Box 6)
    - no. 1501-2000 (Box 7)
    - no. 2001-2500 (Box 7)
    - no. 2501-3050 (Box 7)